原創翻譯  雙語字幕
最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利
翻譯     Murky赤犬  薇薇安  鹽湖涼白開  萊吉
翻譯     辛巴  土方十琦郎  ShellyS  Lynn_寧  Pang
翻譯     魚小淵  小倉  Shishatter  八重  酥ki醬
校對     酸奶還是想養金毛
時間軸   柯基查  影子田園貓  富婆喵羅大  德牧袋  圣伯納圣
后期     8T
總監     somehacker   小酸奶
一條狗的使命
生命的意義是什么
What is the meaning of life?
我們是因為什么原因而生的嗎
Are we here for a reason?
我們為什么要活著
Is there a point to any of this?
起初  我也不知道是怎么回事
First, I had no idea what was going on.
我什么都看不見
I... I couldn't see a thing.
很溫暖
It was warm.
這是我的媽媽
There was my mother.
每一天  我都過得很愉快
Every day, I had fun.
過得愉快就是生命的意義嗎
Was having fun the point?
全部的意義
The whole point?
不對  肯定不會這么簡單的
No, it couldn't be that simple.
這有一只
Here's one.
然后一切都結束了
And then it was over.
你就這樣了
That's it for you.
捕狗隊
不能再玩鬧了
No more fun.
好像這一生過得太短了
It seemed like such a short life.
我做過什么事情嗎
I mean, what exactly did I do?
只是一直玩耍
There was some playing.
吃東西
There was some eating.
還在泥里打滾
I dug in the dirt.
但是當我真正思考起來之后
But when I really thought about it,
我真的沒做什么事
it didn't add up to much.
我回來了
I was back.
我又變成一條小狗了
And I was a puppy again.
我還活著  準備好思考生命的大問題
Alive and ready to ask the big questions.
去刨根問底
To dig for answers.
先讓我進去
Just let me in there.
我在哪呢
Where am I?
你這里還有什么狗
So what else do you have?
還有這一只
Uh, this one here.
-這是什么品種  -這是紅毛獵犬
- What is it? - It's a red retriever.
好狗狗
Nice dog.
不挑食  而且容易訓練
Good breed. Easy to train.
你這里有沒有小一點的品種
You got something smaller?
我還有幾只小約克夏犬
I got some cute yorkies over here.
還有日本狆
I got this Japanese chin.
貴賓犬
Uh, poodle.
這邊是柯基
Corgi over here.
還有博美
Got a pomeranian.
看看這些好東西
Look at all this great stuff.
一定是有人知道我要來
Somebody knew I was coming.
好棒呀
Oh, yeah.
你快看
Hey, look at this.
看看我們找到了什么
What do we have here?
看看這個小家伙
Look at this little guy.
肯定能值幾個錢
Bet it's worth a couple bucks.
第二輪就輸了
Yeah, it was a knockout in the second round.
錢都輸光了  這在等著
I lost everything. Hang tight, guy.
這次該你請客了吧
Now, you're buying this time.
今天不行  伙計
Not today, buddy.
我思考著我的生活
I thought about my life.
我還有好多問題沒有解決
I still had so many questions.
但是我現在只有一個問題
But I kept coming back to the same one:
我要怎么才能喝上水
How do I get a drink of water?
你想要一個冰淇淋嗎
Do you want to get an ice cream?
好呀
Sure.
要什么口味的
What flavor?
媽媽  我聽到里面有聲音
Mom, I hear something in there.
寶貝
Hey, honey.
伊森
Ethan!
媽媽  快過來
Hey, mom, come here.
我的天哪
My god.
它看起來渴極了
It looks so thirsty.
車里面太熱了
It's too hot in there.
我們要把它救出來
I think we need to get him out.
這個門打不開
I can't open the door.
等等  門被鎖上了
Wait, it's locked.
求你了  媽媽
Please, mom.
后退
Okay, stand back.
你個小可憐
You poor thing.
可憐的小東西
You poor, poor thing.
你還好嗎  伙計
How are you, boy?
-沒事吧  -這是什么情況
- Good? - What... what is this?
-媽媽  -一個小男孩
- Mom! - A boy?
-伙計  -小男孩
- Boy... - A boy!
-你還好嗎  -我從來不知道
- Are you okay? - I-I never knew there might be
-世上還有小男孩這樣的存在  -是不是累壞了
- such a thing as a boy. - Tired, huh?
我覺得這小家伙會撐過去的
I think this little guy is gonna make it.
-我們能養他嗎  媽媽  -我不知道
- Can we keep him, mom? - I don't know.
我覺得你爸爸可能不會...
I think your father might not...
我當時就決定了
I decided right then and there
我一定要養這個小男孩
I am definitely keeping this boy.
爸爸  我們能養他嗎
Yeah! Dad, can we keep him?
誰來喂他
Well, who's gonna feed him?
-我來  -誰來給他洗澡
- I will. - Who's gonna clean him?
這些都交給我吧  爸爸
I'll do everything, dad.
-你覺得你已經準備好了嗎  -是的
- You think you're ready to do it? - Yeah.
-我不知道  兒子  -他是個好孩子
- Oh, I don't know, son. - He's a good boy.
是個乖寶寶
He's a good boy.
求你了
Come on, please.
它是只獵犬  爸爸
He's a retriever, dad.
他會幫你拿拖鞋的
He'll fetch your slippers.
下雨天還會幫你拿報紙
And the paper when it rains.
你讓他拿什么都可以
Name something you want fetched.
他都能做到
He can do it.
看  過來
Look. Hey, come here!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
伊森和我覺得
So, Ethan and I discussed that the dog
-他可以照顧好這條狗  -過來  乖孩子
- would be his responsibility. - Come here! Yeah. Good boy.
求你了  爸爸
Please, dad?
他需要朋友
Come on. He needs a pal.
聽著  你和你媽媽一起說服我
All right, this thing that you two are doing,
這不公平
it's dirty pool, okay?
把他帶出去
Take him away.
我要和你媽媽單獨談談
I want to talk to your mother alone.
好的
Okay.
我們可以留它到明天
We'll keep it till tomorrow...
你緊張嗎  伙計  別緊張
You nervous, boy? Don't be.
不會有事的
It'll be okay. Yeah.
我們沒有多少選擇
We don't have much choice.
狗很麻煩的
They make a mess.
-你還要給它洗澡  -拜托
- You gotta clean 'em. - Oh, come on.
-過不了多久他就煩了  -別這樣  吉姆
- He's gonna be bored with it. - Oh, come on, Jim.
你知道的  你知道他三分鐘熱度
You know it. You know how he is.
如果他不同意的話
If he says no,
我們可以離家出走  去找新家
we can run off and go find another family.
伊森
Ethan?
什么
Yeah?
你能養狗了
You have a dog.
太棒了  太好了
Yes! Oh, my gosh, yes!
天吶  謝謝
Oh, my gosh, thank you!
快來  快來
Come on! Come on!
貝利
Bailey.
應該是寶貝的貝  鋒利的利
B-a-I-l-e-y, I-I would think.
我是伊森
And I'm Ethan.
我是他的主人
I'm the owner.
他知道我名字怎么寫嗎
Do you think he knows how to spell my name?
應該知道  親愛的
I would think so, honey.
那就好
Here you go.
伊森·蒙哥馬利
好孩子
Good boy.
貝利
真好
Here you go.
準備好了嗎
Ready?
來吧  貝利
Come on, Bailey.
貝利  坐下
Bailey, sit.
坐下
Sit.
打個滾  打個滾
Roll over. Roll over.
快把那個吐出來
Get that out of your mouth!
Get that out of your mouth.
好了  來這邊
Okay. Come here.
握個手  握個手
Shake your paw. Shake your paw.
來吧  好孩子
Come on. Yeah, good boy!
轉個身  轉個身
Turn around. Turn around.
-來吧  -他在說些什么
- Come on. - What's he saying?
-字數太多了  -來吧  來吧
- It's too many words. - Come on. Okay.
-我還是干這個吧  -過來
- I'm gonna do this now. - Come here.
干得好  干得好
Good job. Good job.
但相比之下  有個詞重復了很多次
But one word got said more than any other.
貝利  貝利  貝利  貝利  貝利
Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
過了一會兒
After a while,
我開始明白這個詞的重要性
I came to understand the words that mattered.
我養了個男孩  他叫伊森
I had a boy, and his name was Ethan.
我也有名字
I got a name.
我叫貝利  貝利  貝利  貝利  貝利
My name was Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
親愛的  真希望知道你和韋斯之間...
Oh, gee, honey, I wish I'd have known that you and Wes were...
我知道了自己在家的地位
I learned my place in the pack.
媽媽喜歡我
Mom liked me.
爸爸喜歡我
Dad liked me.
-是的  是的我知道  -超級喜歡
- Yes. Yes, no, I understand. - A lot.
不好意思  稍等一下
Oh, excuse me. Hold on. Come on.
一邊兒去
Get down a bit.
真替貓感到悲哀
I was sad for the cat.
很明顯他也想當一只狗
Obviously, he wanted to be a dog.
當不成又不是我的錯
Wasn't my fault he couldn't be a dog.
伊森  該睡覺啦
Ethan, it's time to go to bed.
該關燈了好嗎
Time to turn out the light, okay?
好的
Okay.
好了  來吧  來吧
Okay, come on. Come on.
來吧  來吧
Come on. Come on.
"別  別這么做  隊長"
"Don't! Don't do it, cap.
"給他吧  巴基"
"Let him have it, bucky.
"我們得給他點顏色看看"
"We'll pound some sense into this character.
"砰  泰山壓頂"
"Pow! Stomp!
"它沖著我們來了"
"It's coming right at us.
"快跳下去逃生"
Jump for your lives!"
伊森總能想出這樣有趣的游戲
Ethan always came up with such great games.
躲在毯子下說話  真是個天才
Making noise under a blanket. Genius.
每晚睡著之后
Every night as I fell asleep,
我都會覺得養一只伊森真開心
I thought about how happy I was that I had an Ethan.
也慶幸自己不是貓
And that I wasn't a cat.
貝利  到車里來
Bailey, get in the car.
來吧  孩子
Come on, boy.
我們走
Come on!
當家人想讓我出去透透氣時
Whenever the family wanted me to get some fresh smells,
我們都會開車兜兜風
we all got in the car for a ride.
青草  綠樹  蟾蜍  青苔  臭鼬
Grass, tree, toad, moss, skunk,
死臭鼬  池塘
dead skunk, pond,
泥土  山羊
mud, goat.
山羊
Goat!
人們每天都在思索同一個問題
Everyone was asking themself the same question
"為什么不是所有的東西都有山羊味"
"Why can't everything smell like goat?"
臭死了
Ooh, it stinks!
看看是誰來了
Oh, look who's here!
猜猜我們還帶了誰
Guess what we got.
帶了誰
What have you got?
你們帶了誰
What'd you get?
下來吧  貝利
Come on, Bailey.
-我的天  看看它  -一只小狗狗
- Oh, my. Look at this. - Oh! A puppy! -Oh, my gosh.
孩子  看這里
Here, boy. Here.
它要去哪兒
Where's he going?
我常常覺得
Sometimes I thought
生活中東想西想很浪費時間
that trying to make sense out of life could be a waste of time.
直接享受生活  順其自然
Maybe it was better to just really enjoy life
會不會更好呢
and leave it at that.
咦  大家去哪里了
Hey, where'd everybody go?
小雞們呢
Where's all the chickens?
貝利  貝利  貝利
Bailey! Bailey, Bailey!
伊森  伊森  伊森  伊森  伊森
Ethan, Ethan, Ethan, Ethan, Ethan!
老天爺  看看誰來啦
Oh, my goodness! Look who's here!
不知道為什么
For some reason,
他們不愿意和我一起玩這個球
they wouldn't share this ball with me.
跑吧  伊森  快跑
Yes! Run, Ethan, run!
眾所周知
Everybody knows
在球類運動歷史上
there's never been a game in the history of balls
還沒有過狗狗參賽的先例
that can't be improved by having a dog in it.
但這個球長得有點奇怪
But there was something weird about this ball.
寶藏
Treasure.
這才叫生活
Ah, this is the life.
誰還要嗎  吉姆  你的咖啡
Anyone else? Jim, your coffee?
-謝謝  -給你
- Oh, thank you. - Here you go.
大家都到齊了
Here we all are.
對呀  好好吃吧
Yeah. Enjoy your meal.
我喜歡老年人
I liked the old humans.
他們懂我
They got me.
可以不要喂狗吃東西了嗎
Would you please stop feeding the dog?
我們在試著訓練它
We're trying to train him.
我告訴過你了
I told you.
被抓現行了  不好意思
You caught me. I'm sorry.
可以把果醬遞給我嗎
Could you pass me the jam, please?
當我注意力不在吃上時  我就會亂想
When I wasn't thinking about food, my mind wandered.
我為什么會在這里
Why am I here?
有什么目的嗎
What's the purpose?
真爽  接著揉
Oh, yeah. Keep rubbing.
會有更多的培根嗎
And... Might there be more bacon?
看他的盤子里
Oh, look at his plate.
要知道  照這么吃下去
You know, the way you eat,
等你長大了之后  我們幾個加起來
you're gonna grow up to be bigger
都不夠你的塊頭大
than all of us put together.
前提是得有個和平年代
If there's a world to grow up in.
俄國人在古巴布置了導彈
These Russians are putting missiles in Cuba.
我們非得現在說這個嗎
Do we have to talk about that now?
-沒有啊  -對了  吉姆
- No. - So, um, Jim,
聽說你換了份辦公室工作
I hear you're up for a new office job.
不如跟我們講講這個吧
Why don't you tell us about that?
并沒有談成
That didn't work out.
他們想讓他出外勤
Well, they want him in the field.
頂級銷售員年年都有他名字
He's one of the top sellers every year.
我干的活是個燙手山芋
I got the job nobody wants.
吉姆  你非要這樣嗎
Jim, do you have to?
核打擊已經近在咫尺了
We're three seconds away from nuclear annihilation.
我和貝利能離桌了嗎
Uh, can me and Bailey be excused?
當然
Sure.
伊森很難過
Ethan was sad.
我不知道為什么
I didn't know why.
嗨  貝利
Hey, Bailey.
還記得美國隊長嗎
Captain America, remember?
他可以一瞬間就拆掉炸彈
He could take out that bomb in a second.
啪
Pow!
咻
Zap!
看來你挺喜歡呀
Oh, you like it, don't you?
來呀  來呀
Come on. Come on.
就是這樣
Yeah, boy.
貝利  準備好了
Okay, Bailey.
去撿回來
Get it, boy!
加油呀
Come on!
就是這樣伙計
Yeah, boy! Come on.
來  去哪兒了
Come on. Oh, where'd it go?
去哪兒了
Where'd it go?
在這呢  你看那是什么
Come on, boy! Oh! What is that?
把它撿回來
Get it, boy!
加油  加油  拿到它
Oh, come on. Come on, get it!
-我們玩了一下午球  -就是這樣
- We played with that ball all afternoon. - Yeah! Come on!
-伊森特別喜歡這個游戲  -干得漂亮
- Ethan loved it. - Good boy!
撿回來
Get it!
加油  加油
Come on! Come on.
爸  瞧瞧這招
Hey, dad, watch this.
看看他的能耐
Look what he can do.
貝利  準備好了嗎
Okay, Bailey. Ready?
準備好了
Ready.
別動
Stay. Okay.
然后
And...
就是現在
Okay.
上啊貝利
Go, Bailey!
太棒了  松開
Yeah! Out.
真厲害
That's great, pal.
謝了  老爸
Thanks, dad.
來呀來呀
Hey, hey, come on.
對的  對的
Oh, yes. Yes.
來呀  來呀
Come on. Come on.
-祝你今天愉快  -當天氣轉涼時
- You have a great day. - When it got colder outside,
-我們回家了  -再見
- we all went back home. - See ya.
-他不會有事的  再見  -再見
- He'll be fine. Bye. - Bye.
每天早上  一個有輪子的大黃箱子
Every morning, a big yellow box with wheels
都會把伊森從我身邊帶走
took Ethan away from me.
當媽媽也離開后
When mom left the house, too,
我就很孤單
I was lonely,
也會感到餓
and hungry,
而且很無聊
and bored.
幸好他們把貓留下了
At least they left the cat.
我會來教他一些狗的知識
I'd give him his dog lessons.
要學的還很多呢
So much to learn.
狗才不會躲在枕頭下面
No, dogs do not hide under pillows.
過來
Come on. Come...
過來  聞聞我
Come on, sniff me.
聞聞我
Sniff me!
你什么都不知道
You don't know anything.
你總是在清嗓子
You clear your throat a lot.
貝利  不
Oh, Bailey, no.
老爸
Hi, dad.
伊麗莎白
Elizabeth?
-這  這  -伊麗莎白
- This... this... - Elizabeth!
你在嗎
Hello?
那是我的拖鞋
That's my slipper.
貝利  貝利
Bailey! Bailey!
快回來
Come... get back here.
別這樣  貝利
Bailey, no!
快過來  貝利
Bailey, come here.
過來  過來
Come here.Come here.
貝利  過來
Bailey, come here.
-把它給我  -當老爸心情好時
- Give me that. - When dad was in the right mood,
和他一起玩很開心
he was so much fun to play with.
別這樣  松口  松口  松口
Come on, let go. Let go. Let go.
貝利  那不是你的
That's not yours, Bailey.
那是我的  那是我的
That's mine. That's mine!
你給我過來  過來
You come over here. Come on!
伊森  我領導今晚要來
Ethan, my boss is coming over tonight,
不能讓他看到我的辦公室亂成這樣
and he cannot see my office like this.
你明白了嗎
Do you understand?
你得告訴這只狗誰才是老大
You have got to start telling this dog who's boss.
牽著他  快牽著他
Here, take him. Just take him.
然后你說  我才是老大
And you say, "I am the boss!"
你得向他證明誰才是老大
You gotta show him who's boss.
好了  把東西都收拾好
All right, everything goes back where it belongs.
我要這里干干凈凈的
I want this place spick-and-span.
你明白嗎
Do you understand?
你明白了嗎
Well, do you understand?
Do you understand?!
-明白了  -很好
- Yes, sir. - Thank you.
我只想讓事情向我喜歡的那樣發展
I want everything just the way I like it.
干干凈凈
Spick-and-span.
為什么  因為我才是老大  這就是為什么
Why? Because I'm the boss. That's why.
我是老大  你是狗老大
I'm the boss man, and you're the boss dog.
狗老大
Boss dog.
伊森
Ethan.
快來  我們準備吧
Come on. Let's go.
客人馬上就回來了
We got guests coming any minute.
麻利點
Chop-chop.
-吉姆  -怎么了
- Jim?  - What?
你能幫我下嗎
Jim, can you help me?
-怎么了  -我不知道怎么調新加坡司令
- Huh? - I don't know how to make a Singapore sling.
什么
What?
我來教你
Oh, I'll show you.
我可以調威士忌冷飲
I can make a whiskey cobbler.
等下  秘方在這
Wait, here's the recipe.
伊麗莎白  你在  你在干什么
Elizabeth, what are you... What are you doing?
我們需要烈酒
Well, we need spirit...
1907年圣高登斯金鷹硬幣
Saint-gaudens 1907 golden eagle.
是真金
Real gold.
不要啊
No!
伊森對我很好
Ethan was good to me.
-別吞下去啊  -他總是分享他的食物
- Boy! No! - He always shared his food.
還在你嘴里嗎  你吞下去了嗎
Do you have it in your mouth? Did you swallow it?
-雖然不是我最喜歡吃的  -快給我
- Wasn't my favorite treat. - Come on, show me.
-他想要回來  -快給我
- And he wanted it back. - Come on, come on.
為什么
Why?
-我們準時到了  -你好  愛倫
- We made it. - Hello! Ellen.
請進  歡迎光臨
Come in. Welcome.
我很高興我們終于能來這里
I am glad we were finally able to make it out here,
我一直
because I have been wanting to,
想看看外勤辦公室
visit the field office for a while now.
這里真不錯
Oh, yes, and it's... It's so nice and...
郊區很安靜
Quiet out here in the suburbs.
-是的  -是的
- It sure is. Yeah. - Yes.
我們非常開心你們能過來
Well, we're happy to have you.
我是想說我們
Um, so I-I've been meaning to say we...
對你過去一年業績的印象很深刻
Uh, we're real impressed with your numbers this past year, Jim.
你做的非常好
Real impressed.
我很高興你提到這個
You know, I'm glad you brought that up.
我正好也想和你談一下這件事
Uh, I've actually been meaning to talk to you about that.
我覺得既然業績這么好
You know, I-I was thinking, with the numbers so high,
也許是時候讓我不再出差
maybe it's time I get off the road
轉而去坐辦公室了
and take an office position.
我們需要你繼續出差
Well, we... we really need you on the road.
你是整個業務的骨干精英
That's the backbone of the whole operation really.
吉姆  說實話
I'll be honest, Jim.
你是最優秀的旅行推銷員
You are one of our best traveling salesmen.
我意思是 我瘋了才會讓你坐辦公室
I mean, I would be crazy to take you out of the field.
你還在收集硬幣嗎
Um, are you still collecting coins?
當然
Oh, sure.
有精品嗎
What... what's your showpiece?
1907年的圣高登斯金鷹硬幣
1907 Saint-gaudens golden eagle.
赫爾曼  雖然我不懂硬幣
Well, Herman, i don't know anything about coins,
但我知道金鷹硬幣是很特別的
but I know that that is special.
-那是很特別  -那可是珍品
- That is special. - That is a treasure.
是啊  我還從沒親眼見過呢
Yeah, I have never seen one up close before.
-它可不是一般的硬幣  -是的 它還特別漂亮
- It's quite a coin. - Yeah, it's a beauty.
我去拿給你看
I'll show you. I'll go get it.
吃完飯再去吧
Well, maybe after dinner.
那我一會去拿
Let me go get it later.
我可以去玩嗎
May I please be excused?
什么
Huh?
我可以去玩嗎
May I please be excused?
我想帶貝利出去玩
Need to take Bailey out for a walk.
當然了  寶貝
Sure, honey.
拉出來  快
Go on, do it.
求你了  貝利
Please, Bailey.
求你了  貝利  拉出來  快
Please, Bailey, do it. Come on.
他想讓我干什么
What does he want from me?
快拉  快拉
Come on. Come on.
我真想知道他在說什么
I really wish I knew what he was saying.
拉啊  拉啊  快
Go! Go! Come on!
你怎么回事  快拉啊
What's your problem? Come on!
我不知道他為什么不開心  但這讓我很著急
I don't know why he was so upset, but it made me anxious.
而我著急的時候  腸胃蠕動就非常快
And when I'm anxious, things kind of move super fast.
這還是第一次
This was a first.
從來沒見過他這么高興地清理我的糞便
I'd never seen him so happy to clean up after me.
太棒了  找到了
Yes! Found it!
這個甜點的關鍵是不能做得太甜了
It's important it shouldn't be too sweet.
-不  很好吃  -看到了嗎
- No, it's nice. Mmm. - See this?
接下來
Now, this...
你們將
That's something
-迎來一場視覺的盛宴  -不
- for your eyes to feast on. - No!
怎么了
What?
有老鼠
There's a rat.
-什么  什么  -就在那
- What? What? - Right there!
-在哪  不  我討厭老鼠  -在哪
- Where? No, I don't like rats. - Where?
-在哪  -沒事
- Where is it? - It's okay.
桌子下面
Under the table.
-我愛老鼠  -對  捉住它  貝利
- I love rats. - Yeah, go get it, Bailey.
-我什么也沒有看見 -在哪
- I don't see anything. - Where?
-跑到那了  -等等
- It's running over there. - Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait!
抓住狗  抓住狗
Get that dog! Get the dog.
-抓住狗  -貝利
- Get the dog. Get the... - Bailey!
-我什么都沒看到  -給我過來
- I don't see anything. - Come here.
-就在那里  -也許你看到的是小灰
- It's right there. - Maybe you saw Smokey.
-絕對不是小灰  -不  不是小灰
- Definitely not Smokey. - No, it wasn't Smokey.
我真的怕老鼠  我討厭老鼠
I really don't like rats. I don't like rats.
比起你怕它們  是老鼠更怕你吧
It's more scared of you than you are of him.
給我過來  貝利
Come here. Come here, Bailey.
-過來  -你能抓到他嗎  抓住他
- Come here! Come here. - Can you grab him? Grab him.
-吉姆  -貝利  過來
- Jim. - Bailey! Bailey, come here!
過來
Come here!
停下  別跑  貝利
Wait. Please, Bailey.
-你能抓到他嗎  吉姆  -我什么都沒看到
- Can you grab him, Jim? - I don't see anything.
貝利
Bailey!
貝利  過來
Bailey, come here.
我覺得老鼠已經跑了
I think it's gone now.
我好討厭老鼠
Oh, I don't like rats!
貝利
Bailey!
什么情況
What was that?
赫爾曼
Herman!
貝利  過來
Bailey, come here!
快來  快點
Come here! Come on!
你抓到他了嗎  吉姆  抓到沒
You got him, Jim? You got him?
升職什么的再也不用想了
Any chances I had of a promotion, forget it.
爸爸  別這樣
Dad! Dad, stop!
-這不是它的錯  -你讓我們跟傻子一樣
- It's not his fault. It's... - You made us look like fools!
爸爸散發這個味道的時候說話總是很大聲
Dad always talked so loud when he smelled this way.
別懲罰他  都是我的錯
Don't punish him! My fault!
吉姆  你要不要先冷靜一下
Jim, why don't we take a moment before you...
不必了  從現在起  狗待在這里
No, from now on, he stays out here.
它什么也沒做
He didn't do anything!
我不想看到他
I do not want to see him.
別讓我在屋子里再見到他
I do not want to see him in the house.
可是外面冷
But it's cold outside.
他有毛的
Well, he's got fur for that.
我們至少得給他鋪個毯子吧
We should at least set out a blanket.
它只是條狗
It's a dog!
伊森
Ethan?
狗狗  你還好嗎
Hey, boy. Good?
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
都是我的錯
It's all my fault.
盡管我看不到他
Even though I couldn't see him,
我知道伊森那晚很難過
I knew Ethan was very sad that night.
乖狗狗
Hey, boy.
外面太冷了  是吧
It's cold out there, isn't it?
我知道他需要我
I knew he needed me.
我也需要他
And I needed him, too.
真是條乖狗狗
You're a good boy.
準備好了嗎
Ready, boy?
好  過來
Okay. Come here.
來
Come here.
快來  貝利
Come on, Bailey.
好的  準備好了嗎
Okay, boy. Ready?
三  二
Three, two...
一
One!
快來
Come on!
完美
Yeah, boy.
-別這樣  -我們再來一次
- Oh, come on. - Let's do it again.
-太棒了  -好
- Yes! - Yeah!
好球  伊森  傳得漂亮
Nice throw, Ethan. Nice throw.
打得好
Nice play.
伊森  傳得漂亮
Great pass, Ethan.
真厲害  棒極了
Got 'em now. Right on.
你  你每次都把球傳到他那個位置
You-you get it to him every time.
確實
Yeah, exactly.
因為每次我們用那種戰術的時候
'Cause every time we run that play...
所有人都想走在老大旁邊
Everybody wanted to walk next to the Alpha male.
是啊  我就是這個意思
Yeah, that's what I mean.
幾乎所有人
Almost everybody.
-因為每次他都正好在那個位置  -是的
- 'Cause he's right there every single time. - Yep.
-伊森  為什么你總是帶著這條狗  -什么
- Ethan, why do you always have this dog with you? - Hmm?
是用來替代女朋友的還是干嗎的
What? It's like a girlfriend replacement or something?
說得好  托德
Yeah, good one, Todd.
親一個
Give a little kiss? Huh?
我只是問問
I'm just asking.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我很抱歉  托德
Oh, I'm sorry, Todd.
剛才  是不是我的替補女朋友絆倒了你
Did my, uh, girlfriend replacement just trip you?
很好笑
Very funny.
放輕松  伙計  我就是開個玩笑
Relax, man. I'm kidding.
那只狗都在笑你
The dog's laughing at you.
-狗不會笑  你個白癡  -貝利  過來
- Dogs don't laugh, you moron. - Bailey, come here.
好好笑
That's funny.
-都拿好了嗎  -拿好了
- Got everything? - Yeah.
一開始盧傳那腳球的時候
When Lou dropped that pass at the start,
-我還以為我們死定了  -我就知道
- I thought we were done, man. - I know!
來
Here.
貝利  過來
Bailey, come here.
爸爸
Hey, dad.
-你餓了嗎  -餓死了
- You hungry? - I'm starving.
-微波爐里有一盆砂鍋菜  -這樣嗎
- I got a casserole in the oven. - Yeah?
非洲是成千上萬動物的家
Africa is home to hundreds of thousands of animals.
有些看起來很滑稽
Some look comical,
有些  有些讓人望而生畏
some... Some forbidding,
還有些使人著迷到
and some so entrancing that we'd like
讓人想伸開手  觸碰它們
to reach out and touch them...
教練今天讓我打四分衛了
So, uh, coach made me starting quarterback today.
孩子  真不錯
That's great, kid.
爸爸  你下次一定要來看我的比賽
You gotta come to my next game, dad.
我是認真的  我現在打得更好了
I'm serious. I'm better now.
你已經很久沒來看過了
It's been a long time.
好
Okay.
爸爸真可憐
Poor dad.
這地方太棒了
This place is great.
這兒有這么多好聞的
Oh, there's so much to smell here.
還有好吃的
and eat.
到處都是
Oh, it's everywhere.
喂我  喂我
Feed me. Feed me.
你也想玩這個嗎
You want to go next?
伊森身上的味道突然不一樣了
Ethan had a different smell all of a sudden.
一股汗味
A sweaty smell.
有人想坐那個過山車嗎
Who wants to go on that roller coaster?
不知道這跟那個女孩兒有沒有關系
Hmm. I wonder if that girl had anything to do with it.
貝利貝利貝利貝利
Oh! Hey, hey, hey! Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey!
抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
剛剛是那只狗  不是我
That was the dog. That wasn't me.
我不會做那種事的
I wouldn't do that.
或許
Okay, well, maybe
你該教狗懂點禮貌
you should teach your dog some manners.
我在努力  他  他不是太聰明
I've been trying. He's, uh... he's not too smart.
是嗎
Really?
你聽到他剛剛說你什么了嗎
Wow. Did you hear what he said about you?
我看你長得挺聰明的
You look pretty smart to me.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
這么機靈的眼睛
Such intelligent eyes.
我屁股有點癢
My butt itches.
帥哥  你叫什么
What's your name, handsome?
他叫  他叫貝利
He's, uh... he's Bailey.
-貝利  -貝利
- Bailey, yeah. - Bailey.
貝利  你看起來是只特別棒的狗狗
Now, you seem like a very good dog, Bailey.
-是的  -抱歉
- Yeah. - Excuse me?
-玩得不錯  -謝謝你
- Nice job. - Oh. Thank you.
真好
Nice.
別讓他夠著那個
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Keep that away from him.
-好好好  -你真的很擅長這個
- Okay, okay, okay. - You're really good at that.
謝謝
Thanks.
-確實很好  -真的嗎
- Like, really good. - Yeah?
我剛剛在那邊看你來著
I was watching you over there.
不是那樣的
Not like that.
我是說
I mean... yeah.
再見
See ya.
如果我們以后不會再見面的話
Hey, uh, if we never speak again,
我想收回我之前的那句話
I just want to take back what I said before
我剛剛說我的狗不聰明
about my dog not being smart.
但他其實很聰明
He's actually really smart.
絕對比我聰明
Definitely smarter than me.
現在他們倆身上都有那種汗味了
Now they both had a sweaty smell.
你想去  你想去買個熱狗之類的嗎
You want to, uh... you want to get a hot dog or something?
爆米花呢
Popcorn?
好啊
Sure.
走吧
Okay, let's do it.
這邊兒有些賣得不錯的
There's some good ones over here.
貝利  過來
Hey, Bailey, come here.
我想去救他們  但我不知道怎么救
I wanted to save them, but I didn't know how.
-來吧  -不玩了嗎
- Come on. - We done?
-剛剛玩得很開心  -下次不玩了
- Oh, that was good. - Never again.
不  很好玩啊
No! It was fun!
謝謝你呀
Thank you.
伊森有麻煩了
Uh-oh, Ethan's in trouble.
我要死了
I'm gonna die.
我要死了  我要死了
I'm gonna die. I'm gonna die.
-你怎么搞的  -別擔心  伊森
- What's wrong with you? - Oh, don't worry, Ethan.
-我會幫你的  -別別別別別
- I'll help. - Hey, hey, hey, hey, no, no, no, no, no.
待著別動  待著別動
Stay back. Stay back.
-貝利  別別別  -但我在幫你啊
- Bailey, no, no, no. - But I'm helping.
貝利  停下  貝利貝利貝利貝利貝利
Bailey, stop! Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey,
貝利  停下停下停下停下
Bailey, stop, stop, stop, stop. Hey. No.
謝謝你  謝謝你們倆送我回來
Thank you. Thank you both for the ride.
我剛剛為什么要吃這么多熱狗
Why did I eat so many meat logs?
我們應該一起做些什么
Yeah, we should do something.
會很不錯的
Yes, that would be nice.
今天玩得很開心
It was fun.
是的
It was.
除了要買下28個熱狗  都很好
Except for having to pay for 28 hot dogs.
不好意思
excuse me.
-你最好快點走了  快點走吧  -好吧
- Yeah, you better go. You better go quick. - Okay.
-拜拜  -拜拜
- Okay. Bye. - See ya.
從那時起
From that moment on,
這個女孩兒就成了我們的一員
the girl was a member of our pack.
我喜歡她
I liked her.
而且她聞起來像餅干的味道
Plus she smelled like biscuits.
去  去  貝利
Go! Go, Bailey!
我們每天都在一起
We spent every day together.
-真是好孩子  -準備好了嗎貝利
- That a boy. - Ready, Bailey?
-好了  扔  扔  -好了  扔了
- Yeah. Go, go, go. - Ready? Okay, here we go.
-真棒  -跳的真好
- Oh! Good boy! - What a dive.
那是什么
What was that?
-真棒  -游啊
- Oh! Good boy! - Swim!
拿回來
Bring it back!
真棒
That a boy.
-快過來  -真棒  真棒
- Come here, boy. - That a boy. That a boy.
-來  -真棒
- Come on. - Oh, good boy!
-真棒  真棒  -是啊  真棒
- Good boy. Good boy. - Yeah, good boy.
小心頭
Watch your head.
真棒
Good boy.
-不  這不可以  -不
- No, it's not okay. - No.
反正我也要走了
Besides, I'm going.
-為什么  -因為你從不聽我說話
- Why?  - You don't listen!
每次我問你那些東西去哪了的時候...
Every time I ask you where something comes from...
你告訴我  你告訴我那些東西去哪了
You tell me! You tell me where it's going!
因為是我掙來的  我掙來的  我掙來的
Cause I earn it! I earn it! I earn it!
要不我們去城里吧
You, uh... you want to go to town instead?
好的
Yeah.
-貝利  -走吧  貝利
- Bailey. - Come on, Bailey!
我們一起嚎叫
We howled together.
有時候我們就坐在車里
And sometimes we would sit in the car
哪里都不去
not even going anywhere.
伊森和漢娜會纏在一起舔對方
Ethan and Hannah would wrestle and lick each other.
他們是在搶食物嗎
Are they fighting over food?
也許漢娜在她嘴里藏了點什么
Maybe Hannah's hiding something in her mouth.
沒  什么也沒有
Nope. Nothing in there.
我的天...  你是怎么了
Oh, my... What's going on with you?
它喜歡你
Man, he loves you.
但是不管他
But no matter how much
多努力在那里找食物  他從沒找到過什么
he looked for food in there, he never found anything.
而且他
And he looked.
找了很多遍
A lot.
你能感覺的到
You can feel it.
夏天要結束了
Summer's ending.
是最好的夏天了
Best summer ever.
是的
Yeah.
我不想回學校
I don't want to go back to school.
你想的
Yes, you do.
我想
I do?
是的
Yes.
你會在一個好學校
You are gonna get a big football scholarship
得到一大筆橄欖球獎學金
at a good school.
我會申請那個學校
And then I'm gonna apply to that school
然后得到一筆學術獎學金
and get an academic scholarship.
我們都會上大學
And then we'll both be at college,
然后永遠不會分開
and we'll never be apart.
你把一切都計劃好了啊
You've got it all planned out, huh?
的確是的
Yes, indeed.
這是個好計劃
That's a good plan.
對吧  貝利
Right, Bailey?
什么  你說了什么
What? What did you say?
-拜拜  -拜
- See ya. - Bye.
拜
Bye!
明天見
See you tomorrow.
真乖
Good boy.
我得走了
I gotta go.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我要去喝點啤酒
I'm getting some beer.
我只是想讓你聲音放小一點
All I ask is for you to lower your voice.
-我就這點...  -別說了  別說了
- That's all I... - Stop, stop. Just stop!
你能小聲一點嗎
Will you please just keep it down?
我的父母就在樓下  吉姆  你別鬧了
My parents are upstairs, Jim. You need to stop.
好吧  對不起  你是對的
Oh, I'm sorry. You know, you're right.
好吧  那我就不鬧了
Fine. I will stop doing it, then.
我走行吧  我就直接走
I'll just go! I'll just leave.
你覺得這樣好嗎
Does that sound good to you?
-出來吧  -你覺得這樣好嗎
- Come on, boy. - Does it sound good to you?
-我不知道  你說呢  -你覺得
- Well, I don't know. You tell me. - Will that be
這樣好嗎  我就這樣走了你高興嗎
good for you? Will you be happy then if I just...?
不  告訴我  告訴我你高不高興
No, just tell me. Just tell me if you'll be happy.
-別說了  走吧  -我會走的
- Stop it. Just go! - Oh, I'm gonna go!
好吧  我走
Fine, I'll go.
你能不能進屋來...
Will you just come back inside...
別說了伊麗莎白  閉嘴  閉嘴
Stop it, Eliz... Shut up! Shut up!
進屋來吧  我是在幫你  吉姆
Just come back inside. I am trying to help you, Jim.
你是在幫我  你想幫我
You're trying to help me? You want to help me?
你是我妻子  伊麗莎白
You're my wife, Elizabeth.
-你應該支持我  -我是在支持你
- You should support me. - I do support you.
-你能不能進屋來...  -小伙子
- Will you just come back inside... - Hey. Hey, pal.
你在監視我嗎
You spying on me?
什么
What?
你在監視我嗎
You spying on me?
-別吼他  吉姆  -過來
- Leave him alone, Jim. - Come here.
-別吼他  -你有什么想說的嗎
- Leave him alone. - No. You got something to say?
-我剛到家  -過來
- I just got home. - Come here.
-看看他是怎么看著我的  -不
- Look at how he looks at me. - No.
-我真討厭他這樣看著我  -沒事的  伊森
- I am so sick of the way you look at me. - It's okay, Ethan.
-沒關系  -放松  放松
- It's okay. - Just relax. Relax.
-看看他是怎么看著我的  -你在干什么
- Look at how you look at me. - What are you doing?
-這跟他沒關系  -你別管
- This has nothing to do with him. - Stay out of it.
-這跟他沒...  -你別管
- This has nothing... - You stay out of it!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
冷靜  冷靜一下  冷靜一下
Easy. Take it easy. Take it easy.
-你是對的  -我的天...
- You're right. - God...
你是對的
You're right.
我要...
I'm gonna...
你別想再碰她一下
Don't you ever touch her again!
你聽見了沒
You hear me?
你得走了
You gotta go.
媽媽  他得走了
Mom, he's gotta go.
他不能待在這了
He can't stay here.
媽媽  你沒事吧
Mom, you okay?
沒事  對不起
Yeah. I'm sorry.
你確定你什么都帶著了嗎
Sure you got everything?
讓他跟我說句話
Just let her talk to me.
上車吧  爸爸  -我搞得定
- Just get in the car, dad. - I got it.
從那時起
From that moment on,
伊森變成我們的頭了
Ethan was the leader of our pack.
當我們回家后  情況和之前不一樣了
When we went home, things were different.
爸爸走了
Dad was gone.
那只貓躲了我好久
That cat had been hiding from me for a while.
現在我找到他了
And now I got it.
我找到他了
I found him!
好吧  對不起
Okay, sorry.
天哪
Geez!
上啊  紅80  紅80
Go! Red 80. Red 80.
-加油  伊森  -觸底  準備  一次進攻
- Let's go, Ethan! - Down, set, hut!
-就是這樣  -在上面
- That's it. - Over the top.
防守的好
Good block.
猛虎隊奪得首攻
First down, tigers.
外接手接到傳球
Pass caught by wide receiver...
好樣的  伊森
Way to go, Ethan!
猛虎隊領先十分
First and ten for the tigers.
加油  猛虎隊
Come on, tigers!
準備  就位  開始
Down, set, hut!
加油  加油
Yeah! Yeah!
猛虎隊觸地得分
Touchdown, tigers!
真是太精彩了
That was amazing.
媽媽
Mom.
天吶
No.
全額獎學金  四年
Full scholarship. Four years.
我的天吶  真的嗎
Oh, my gosh! Really?
好了  好了  行啦
Okay, okay. Come on.
-真的嗎  -嗯
- Really? Oh! - Yeah.
-在這里等著好嗎  狗老大  -好
- Okay, you wait here. Okay, boss dog? - Okay.
等著  我去給你弄些吃的  好嗎
You wait here. I'll get you something to eat, okay?
知道啦
I just said okay.
乖狗狗
Good boy.
來吧  寶貝兒  燒起來
Come on, baby! Let it burn!
燒  燒  燒  好耶
Go, go, go, go, go! Yes!
-好...  -怎么回事
- Ye... - What?
哈  跳梁小丑
Ah, some jokers.
-干得好  -打得真棒
- Good job. - Great game, great game.
-我來放哨  -伊森
- I'm keeping watch. - Hey, Ethan!
-一切安全  -你還好嗎
- All clear. - How you doing?
有情況
What?
他怎么來了
What was he doing here?
而且和往常一樣  心情很差
And in one of his bad moods, too.
我聞得出來
I could smell it.
走啦  快點
Come on, let's go.
-快點  -遺傳了他媽媽的智商
- Come on. - Got his brains from his mom, huh?
是啊  但我還是沒拿到獎學金
Yeah, I didn't get a scholarship, though.
爸爸
Hey, dad.
兒子
Hey, pal.
你怎么...  你怎么在這兒
What are you, uh... What are you doing here?
我看到了...  我今晚看到你了  伊森
Oh. Well, I saw you... I saw you tonight, Ethan.
-你打得很棒  -你看了比賽
- You did good. - You were at the game?
是啊
Yeah.
投球投得不錯
You got a good arm.
順利被錄取了吧
So everything's going good, huh?
-這小子厲害吧  -爸爸
- This guy, huh? - Dad.
-比賽打得真不錯  -爸爸
- Good game, huh? - Dad, hey.
-贏了比賽都很激動吧  -爸爸
- We're all excited for the big win, huh? - Dad.
都為這小子歡呼吧
Let's cheer for this guy!
你能不能別這樣  爸爸
You don't have to do this right now, dad.
來吧  來吧
Come on! Come on, huh?
別這樣好嗎
Would you stop this?
好吧
Hey. All right.
好了  走吧
Come on, let's go.
給你漢堡
Want your burger?
是貝利的
For Bailey?
狗老大  真乖
Hey, boss dog. Good boy.
原來伊森的世界也并非十全十美啊
So it's not all perfect in Ethan land, huh?
難怪你要逃到密歇根去了
Now I know why you're going to Michigan, man.
想離你的酒鬼老爸遠點兒嗎
Get away from that alchy father of yours.
-你最好閉嘴  托德  -是嗎
- You should shut up, Todd. - Oh, yeah?
你  你不想讓所有人都知道
You-you don't want everyone here knowing
你老爸是個酒鬼嗎
that your father's a drunk?
伊森  我還得趕公交  走吧
Ethan, I have to catch my bus. Please.
顯然大家都知道了
It's pretty obvious.
-我們走吧  -好  一會兒就走
- Can we go? - Yeah, we're going soon.
他女朋友也開始心疼他了
Oh, oh, and his girlfriend's fighting his battles, too.
如果密歇根州大知道這樣的你...
If Michigan state knew the real Ethan...
天吶
Whoa!
我說過讓你閉嘴  托德
I told you to shut up, Todd.
我不喜歡這個味道
I don't like that smell.
我們上車吧
Please get in the car.
貝利  快點
Bailey, come on!
貝利  快過來  上車
Bailey, let's go. Get in the car.
什么聲音
What was that?
是松鼠嗎
Could that be that squirrel?
完美
Perfect.
托德闖進了我們的地盤
Todd was on our territory.
我真想咬他
Oh, I wanted to bite him.
但是伊森不讓我咬人
But I remembered Ethan telling me no biting.
不管了
Then I forgot.
停下  停下  別咬
No, no, no, no, no!
伊森
Ethan.
貝利
Bailey.
貝利  別吵
Bailey, shut up.
媽媽
Mom!
媽媽  媽媽
Mom, mom, mom!
快起來  醒醒
Get up, get up, get up.
快點  快點  起來
Quick, quick. Come on, quick!
-我們得出去  -不行  出不去了
- We gotta get out. - We can't. We can't.
這里  從窗戶走
Come. The window.
-快過來  -天吶
- Come here. - Oh, god.
著火了  著火了
Fire! Fire!
-跳下去  -不行  太高了
- You gotta jump. - It's too high.
快把你的床單也拿來
Get your sheets! Get your sheets!
-給你  -把床單綁起來
- Here. Here. - I just want to tie these together.
附近有梯子嗎
Anyone have a ladder handy?
我們得把他們弄下來
We gotta help 'em down!
-天吶  -這是唯一一條生路了
- Oh, god. - It's the only way, okay?
-里面有多少人  -對 就這樣
- How many people are in the house? - Okay.
快去檢查一下房子后面
Check the back of the house.
快搭把手
Somebody give me a hand!
-快  快  小心  -接住你了
- Go, go, go. - We got you.
好了  接住了  接到她了
Okay, we got you. Got her.
-接到你了  -好了
- We got you. We got you. - Okay.
乖狗狗  乖狗狗
Good boy. Good boy.
我去后邊檢查
I'll check around back!
我就在你后邊
I'm here-- right behind you.
好了
Okay.
不
No!
天吶
Oh!
-快點  -我能幫什么忙嗎
- Come on. - Is there anything I can do?
我們得幫他下來
We gotta help him down.
小心  伊森
Come on, Ethan.
你得跳下來  孩子
You need to jump, son.
伊森  快跳
Ethan, jump!
伊森
Ethan!
-你能動嗎  -我的腿
- Okay, can you move? - My leg!
-好了  堅持住  -一  二  三
- All right, come on. -One, two, three.
小心腿
His leg.
腿好疼
My leg.
-你會沒事的  -沒事的  放心吧
- You're gonna be all right. -It's okay. You're okay.
沒事了
It's okay.
誰來牽走這條狗
Somebody hold this dog.
貝利  貝利  你不能去
Hey, Bailey. Bailey, no.
不行
No.
跟著他  和他待一起
Go with him. Go with him.
別動
No.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
會沒事的  乖狗狗  他會回來的
It's going to be okay, boy. He'll be back.
安靜
Easy.
不要
No. Hey, hey.
-不要  停下  -有只狗
- Don't! Stop! - There's the dog.
來人抓住那條狗
Somebody get the dog.
你跑什么呢  孩子
What you running from, son?
我發誓  這是場意外  我
I swear, it... It was an accident. I...
不如你告訴我們發生了什么
Why don't you tell us what happened?
我有一支煙花
I-I-I had a firework...
你得跟我們走一趟
I think you should come with us.
但是不要  拜托  拜托
But don't... Please... please just...
這是場意外
It was an accident.
弗蘭  弗蘭  過來  過來
Fran! Fran, come on, come on, come on.
-是他們到了嗎  -他們到了  是他們
- They're here? - They're here, they're here.
-好  -小心點  親愛的
- Okay. - Be careful, dear.
我有小心
I'm... I'm being careful.
有小心
I'm being careful.
親愛的
Hey, sweetie.
見到你真好
Good to see you.
看看你
Oh, look at you.
來  來  讓我
Here, here, let...
-我能行  -弗蘭  弗蘭  弗蘭
- I-I got it. - Fran, Fran, Fran, Fran.
別這樣  別
Stop it. Stop.
見到你真好  伊森
Good to see you, Ethan.
你也是
Yeah. You, too.
我一整天都在烤東西
I've been baking all day.
你的房間都整理妥當了  伊森
Got your room all set up for you, Ethan.
你們來住這里真好
It's so good to have you here.
伊森再也不想玩了
Ethan never wanted to play anymore.
貝利
Oh, Bailey.
抱歉
I'm so sorry.
盡管他走到哪兒
Even though he carried
都帶著那根漂亮的新棍子
a great new stick everywhere he went.
貝利  不要
Bailey, come on. Hey!
-不不不  貝利  -貝利
- No, no, no, no, no, Bailey. - Bailey.
別咬  別咬
Come on. Come on.
我再也請不動他和我玩了
I couldn't make him play with me.
他只想睡覺
All he wanted to do was sleep.
現在我的自由時間充裕  所以交了個新朋友
I had a lot of free time now, so I made a new friend.
它像只小馬
It was like a small horse.
或巨狗
Or a giant dog.
它身上有種獨特的氣味
With its own special smell
十分美妙又特別惡心
that was so wonderful and disgusting.
真希望我能進去打滾
Oh, I wished I could roll in it.
我們玩得超開心
Oh, we had fun.
直到它不高興了
Until we didn't.
至少漢娜仍會來玩
At least Hannah still came around.
貝利
Hi, Bailey.
你好
Hi. Hi.
我也想你了
I missed you, too.
好狗狗  好狗狗
Good boy. Good boy.
真是一只好狗狗
Ah, you're such a good boy.
來  來
Come on. Come on!
你  你想去池塘那邊嗎
You, um... do you want to go to the pond?
我做了些三明治
I made some sandwiches.
好啊
Yeah.
我是說
I mean...
如果你想的話
Yeah, if you want.
我只是  想著如果我們離開屋子
I just... I thought it'd be nice
讓你出去轉轉  挺好的
if we could get out of the house, get you out.
怎么了
What?
漢娜  我知道你是好心
Look, Hannah, it's nice for you to try,
但是你不用  不用這樣做
but you don't have to... You don't have to do this.
你不用幫我
You don't have to help me.
我不是為了你
I'm not doing it for you.
是為了我們  我想
I'm doing it for us. I want...
不  你就是為了我才這么做的
No, you're doing this for me.
三周后你就去上大學了
You leave for college in three weeks.
但我隨時會回來的
But I'll be back all the time.
對  但我會待在這里
Uh-huh, and I'll be here.
拖著這條廢腿
With that.
你不能再自怨自艾了
You have to stop feeling sorry for yourself.
你不能為我這么做  漢娜
You can't do this for me, Hannah.
我愿意為你做任何事
I'd do anything for you.
我不認為我們應該繼續在一起了  漢娜
I don't think we should be with each other anymore, Hannah.
我們不該繼續在一起了
We shouldn't be with each other anymore.
不會有結果的
It's not gonna work.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你為什么要這樣
Why are you doing this?
貝利
Bailey.
好狗狗
Good boy.
乖
Yeah.
你想玩球嗎
You want your ball?
好  給你球
Okay, here's your ball.
去吧
Go on.
再見  貝利
Bye, Bailey.
等等  等等  不要啊
Wait. Wait, no.
別走  留下
No, stay.
我真的很想念漢娜
I really missed Hannah.
伊森也想念他
Ethan missed her, too.
我能感覺到
I could tell.
伊森  我做了三明治
Ethan, I made you a sandwich.
放在后座上  好嗎
I'm gonna put it in the backseat, okay?
-好了  弗蘭  -貝利  貝利  貝利
- All right, Fran. -Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
好狗狗
Good boy.
你會想我的  對嗎
You're gonna miss me, huh?
我也會想你的
I'm gonna miss you, too.
別悶悶不樂的  女士們
Don't look so glum, women.
這是所很好的農業學校
It-it's a good agricultural school.
他能學到經營這片農場
He's gonna learn everything he needs to know
所需的各種知識
about running this farm.
對  當然
Yes, absolutely. Yes.
走  過來
All right, go on. Come on.
最好牽住它
Better grab him.
它理解不了的
He's not gonna understand.
來這里
Come here.
-好狗狗  好狗狗  -你牽好狗了嗎
- Good boy. Good boy. - Have you got the dog?
我們到這里來
Let's come here.
-站住  貝利  站住  -過來  狗狗
- Stay, Bailey, stay. - Come on, boy.
天氣真好  是吧
Great day, huh?
它都長這么大了
He's so grown-up.
它在干嗎
What's he doing?
我的天
Oh, my goodness.
好狗狗  貝利
Good boy, Bailey.
幫我保存它  好嗎  貝利
You keep that for me, okay, Bailey?
-接住了  -是啊
- Caught it. - Yeah.
再見  伊森
Bye, Ethan.
一路順風
Drive safe.
拜拜  伊森
See you, Ethan!
不要  貝利
No, Bailey.
-站住  -你牽住它  親愛的
- Stay. - You got him, honey?
站住  我們玩接球呢
Stay? We're playing fetch.
貝利
Bailey!
我們已經很久沒一起玩了
It's been so long since we've played.
貝利
Bailey.
我喜歡這個新版本的接球游戲
I like this new version of fetch.
你是不是瘋了  狗老大
You're crazy, you know that, boss dog?
只是下次能不能...別開這么遠
Maybe not... Drive so far next time.
幫我照看好這里的一切  好嗎
Take care of things around here for me, okay, boy?
我很快就回來
I'll be back soon.
答應我
Promise.
好了  去吧  回家
Come on. Go on. Go home.
人類很復雜
Humans are complicated.
他們總做些狗狗不懂的事情
They do things dogs can't understand.
比如離別
Like leave.
伊森和我注定要在一起
Ethan and I were meant to be together.
但如果伊森不在了
But if there was no Ethan,
我活著還有什么意義
what was the point of my being here?
也許意義就在于不要尋找意義
Maybe the point was not to look for a point.
好了  等一下
Okay, hold on. Hold on.
我很快回來  貝利
I'll be right back, Bailey.
現在  一切都以緩慢的步調流逝
Everything moved at a slower pace now.
沒關系
Which was okay,
反正我也不想再跑了
because I never felt like running anymore.
我經常覺得累
I was tired all the time.
不再想著玩兒
I didn't feel like playing anymore.
哪怕是跟小馬狗
Not even with horse-dog.
貝利
Hey, Bailey.
你還好嗎  孩子
Are you okay, boy?
比爾
Bill?
-小心點  當心... -好的
- Careful. Keep a... - Okay.
它怎么了
Okay, let's see what we have here.
它的眼睛看起來不大對勁
His eyes just didn't look right.
有...有很多眼屎
They just, uh... they were... They were kind of rheumy.
而且它...老是喘氣
And he... and he was panting, he was, uh...
呼吸很沉重
His breathing was labored.
它身上還起了個小腫塊
He's-he's also got this little lump in his, uh...
對  它有沒有
Oh, yeah. Has he been drinking
-大量喝水和尿尿  -沒有
- a lot of water and peeing? - No.
昏昏欲睡  它...不太想出去散步了
Lethargic, so he... he doesn't want to go for walks anymore?
我都不得不把它抱進車里
I had to carry him into the car.
醫生  你覺得  我們能為它做點什么
What can we do for him, doctor? What do you think?
我們...我們可以做個檢查
Well, we-we... We could do testing,
但恐怕還是一樣的結果
but I'm afraid that it would probably be the same results.
它的...它的腎功能在衰退
His... his kidneys are shutting down.
我們能不能...
Can we just...
大家都很難過
Everyone was so sad,
但是我已經沒力氣去逗他們開心了
but I was too tired to cheer them up.
喬伊斯醫生  我能不能借用下你電話
Dr. Joyce, can I, uh... Can I use your phone?
當然可以
Yes. Oh, absolutely.
醫生  醫生  如果這是個人
Doctor, doctor, uh, if this was a person,
如果它是個人  你是獸醫
if this was a person... you're the veterinarian...
如果它是個人  是不是意味著...
if this was a person, would you say that...
你好
Uh, hello.
我想找伊森
Yeah, uh, I'm looking for Ethan.
我是他外公  比爾
It's his grandpa, Bill.
伊森  我是外公
Ethan, it's grandpa.
伊森
Ethan.
你來了嗎
Are you here?
我聞不到你
I can't smell you.
你在哪兒
Where are you?
貝利
Hey, Bailey.
他來了
There he was.
我知道他很難過
I could tell he was still sad.
我不想讓他難過
I didn't want him to be sad.
小笨狗
Doodle dog.
狗老大
Boss dog, huh?
我知道我來到這世上是為了愛伊森
I knew I was here to love Ethan
讓他快樂
and make him happy.
貝利  貝利  貝利  貝利
Oh, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
我不想就這樣離開他
I didn't want to leave him like this.
乖孩子
Good boy.
乖孩子  貝利
Good boy, Bailey.
別擔心
Don't worry.
他只會感覺到脖子上一丁點...小刺痛
He'll just feel a little... A little prick in his neck,
然后就可以安息了
and then the pain will go away.
一切又重新開始了
And then it happened again.
媽媽  乳汁
The mother, the milk,
舌頭  溫暖
the tongue, the warmth.
我回來了
I was back.
但為什么
But why?
伊森去哪兒了
Where was Ethan?
有些東西也不見了
Other things were missing, too.
我怎么沒有...
I didn't have a...
什么  我是個女孩
What? I'm a girl?
過來  過來
Come on, come on!
乖孩子  乖孩子
Good girl, good girl.
我的主人很嚴肅
My man was very serious.
注意
Look.
-過  過  -我們工作很辛苦
- Over. Over. Good girl! - We worked hard.
就算是玩  也被他搞得像在工作
Even when we played, he made it feel like work.
放松  下  下
Easy. Down, down.
找到沃利  搜尋開始
Find Wally. Search! Go!
沃利真是讓人頭疼
Wally was a disaster,
老在掉東西
always losing pieces of clothing.
你找到他了
You found him.
真棒
Good job. Okay.
埃莉  芝加哥警犬
難道這就是我的使命
So this is my purpose?
跟玩樂無關
It's not about fun.
-跟伊森無關  -來  乖孩子
- It's not about Ethan. - Come on. Good girl.
我的工作就是搜尋  查找
My job is to seek, find
和展示
and show.
真棒  乖孩子
Good job. Good job.
但即使我做得很棒
But even when I did a good job,
我的主人也還是不開心
my man was still sad.
他很孤單
He was lonely.
我知道曾經有人也住在這里
I could smell someone else used to live here,
但他們的氣味很微弱
but their scent was faint.
他們已經很久沒出現在這屋子里了
They hadn't been around in a long time.
這時我開始意識到
That's when I realized
世上最糟糕的事  莫過于孤單
being alone might be the worst thing that could happen to you.
我知道想念一個人是什么感覺
I knew how it felt to miss someone.
他也在想念某個人嗎
Did he miss someone, too?
不可以
Stop that.
怎么了
What?
睡你自己的床  快去
Dog bed-- now.
埃莉...
Ellie...
睡自己的床  去
Dog bed-- now.
為什么我要聽他的
Why did I listen to him?
我不想走
I didn't want to go.
而且我知道  他也不希望我走
And I could tell he didn't want me to go, either.
天啊
Oh, gosh.
能不能讓我省點心
Would you give me a break?
不許發牢騷
No whining.
這是槍
Gun.
槍聞起來有股刺鼻的味道
Gun had a smell that stung my nose.
乖乖的
Steady.
坐好
Stay.
放松
Relax.
習慣了就好了
Get used to it.
要堅強
Stay strong.
乖狗狗
Good girl.
怎么了
Yes?
什么
What?
那個我也會
I could do that, too.
我找不到拒絕的理由
You know, I don't see why not.
上來  上來
Come on. Come on.
這是她昨天穿的毛衣
That's the sweater that she was wearing yesterday.
-好的  女士  -她今天穿了
- Okay, ma'am. - Today, she had on
藍色牛仔褲和藍色外套
blue jeans and a blue jacket.
你記得是什么時候...
Do you remember what time it was...
我們接到了這里傭人的報案
We got called here on a domestic.
在我們到這之前  是一起綁架案
By the time we got here, it was kidnapping.
前男友  攜帶武器
Ex-boyfriend, armed.
綁架了12歲的女孩
Took the 12-year-old girl.
這是什么
What is this?
這是她在被綁架前一天穿過的衣服
This is the last item of clothing she was wearing.
知道了
Okay.
走吧  我們走
Come on. Come on.
一位目擊者打電話稱
Got a partial plate called in
有一輛藍色豐田正向東開向水庫
on a blue Toyota heading east toward the reservoir.
收到  我們馬上過去
Copy that. We're on our way.
埃莉  埃莉
Ellie. Ellie.
快找
Find.
快找  埃莉
Find, Ellie.
真乖  好好找
Good girl. Good find.
椒鹽卷餅  披薩  熱狗
Pretzel. Pizza. Hot dog.
橡膠  列車  出租車
Rubber. Train. Cab.
咖啡  毛衣  女孩  穿毛衣的女孩
Coffee. Sweater. Girl? Sweater girl!
女孩  女孩
Girl! Girl!
快
Come on.
快點  快
Come on. Come on.
就是那個女孩
That a girl.
追上他  追上他
Get him! Get him!
站住
Halt!
警察
Police!
站住
Halt!
追上他  抓住他
Get him, girl. Get him!
追上他  埃莉
Get him, Ellie!
我說  站住
I said halt!
慢慢地
Slowly!
放開她
Let her go!
別動  站住
Hold it! Hold it!
停下
Stop!
站住
Hey!
Halt!
-這里  -在這  她在這
- Hey! - Hey, hey, there she is.
-在這里  這里  -我們來了  有我們呢
- Hey, hey. - We've got you. We've got you.
-真棒  干得漂亮  -走吧
- Good girl. Good girl. - There you go.
松開
Release!
好了  我們抓住他了  抓住他了
All right, we got him. We got him.
-起來  -走
- Get up. - Let's go.
快  起來
Come on, get up!
快點
Come on.
這里是警犬K27
This is canine unit k-27.
我需要立刻...
I'm gonna need immediate...
支援
assistance.
我的狗中槍了
My dog's been shot.
重復  警犬中槍
I repeat, canine shot.
我一直討厭中槍
I always hated getting shots.
這絕對是我受過的最重的槍傷
This was definitely the worst shot I ever got.
埃莉
Ellie.
你會沒事的
You're gonna be okay.
你是條很棒的狗
You're a good dog.
從卡洛斯的語氣中我能聽出
I could tell from Carlos's voice
我干得不錯
I'd done a good job.
你是條很棒的狗
You're a good dog.
我需要休息一下
I need to rest.
我能就在你的床上睡覺嗎
Can I just sleep in your bed?
那是一種不同的生活
That was a different life.
沒什么樂趣可言  真的
Not so much fun, really.
但是我做得不錯
But I did good work.
開始了
Here we go.
現在我很小并且注意力集中
Now I'm tiny and all ears.
你好啊  小可愛
Hi, you.
你是這世界上最可愛的小狗狗嗎
Are you the cutest little puppy in the world?
她聞起來真香
She smelled good,
像陽光和椒鹽卷餅的味道
like sunshine and pretzels.
我覺得你是
I think you are.
是嗎  你想和我一起回家  對嗎
Oh, yeah. You want to come home with me, huh?
好了  你得和我一起回家
Okay, you gotta come home with me.
你和我一起回家  好嗎
You gotta come home with me, huh?
你想幫我嗎
Are you gonna help me with this?
怎么了
What's happening?
你要去哪  過來
Where are you going? Come here.
怎么了
What's going on?
What's going on, huh?
我看得出來她很傷心
I could tell she was sad.
我得哄她開心
I needed to cheer her up.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我的尾巴呢
Where's my tail?
咦  我的尾巴去哪了
Hello? Where's my tail?
好了  狗狗  好了
Okay, boy. All right.
快  快  咱們走
Come on. Come on, let's go.
瑪雅去哪都帶著我
Everywhere she went, Maya brought me along.
真是太棒了
Which was great.
根據美國哲學家
According to the American philosopher
查爾斯·桑德斯·皮爾士
Charles Sanders Peirce,
人類只用符號思考
human beings think only in signs.
她總是給我帶吃的
She always brought me something to eat.
我都快忘了餓肚子的感覺了
I almost forgot what it was like to be hungry.
幾乎
Well, almost.
-你好  -你好
- Hey. Hi. - Hi.
-好可愛的狗  -謝謝
- Cute dog. - Uh-huh. Thanks.
我們中的幾個
Um, listen, uh, a few of us
準備組成一個學習小組
are putting together a study group.
我們準備在伍德福德自習室一起討論學習
We're meeting at the Woodford common room.
我們希望你能加入
We'd love for you to join us.
我很想去  但是我已經有安排了  所以...
Um, I would, but I have plans, so...
但是我還沒說我們什么時候討論學習
Oh... oh, but I didn't say when we was meeting.
不
No.
不  我只是...  我很忙  我...
No, I just... I'm busy. I...
我知道我會很忙...
Like, I know I'm gonna be busy and, like...
我還得照顧我的狗  所以我...
I got my dog, so I gotta...
謝謝你  我得走了
Thank you. I gotta go.
我很抱歉  我得去遛狗了  所以...
I'm sorry. I have to take my dog out, so...
-好吧  -但還是謝謝你
- Okay. - But thank you.
好吧
Okay.
-也許下次有機會再約  -好
- Maybe next time. - Uh, yeah.
我不知道我是怎么了  蒂諾
I don't know what's wrong with me, Tino.
或許多認識些人挺好的  但是...
Like, yeah, maybe it would be nice to meet people, but...
不  我也該一個人學習因為...
No, also I should just study alone 'cause...
慢著點  慢著點
Slow down. Slow down.
我只有小短腿
My legs are barely even legs.
我覺得自己真蠢
Ugh! I feel like such an idiot.
我很快明白了  雖然瑪雅總是在說話
I learned quickly that even though Maya talked all the time,
她很像卡洛斯
she was a lot like Carlos.
我們的小團體里沒有別人了
There was no one else in our pack.
只有瑪雅和我
Just Maya and me.
但我開始懂她了
But I'm starting to get her.
事實上  我能讀她的心
Actually, I can read her mind.
你知道我在想什么嗎
You know what I'm thinking?
-薯條  -薯條
- Chips. - Chips.
你知道我在想什么嗎
You know what I'm thinking?
-披薩  -披薩
- Pizza. - Pizza.
一定要是披薩啊
Please. Pizza.
-嗨  克里斯  -嗨
- Hey, Chris. - Hi.
-給你 謝謝  -拜拜
- Here you go. - Thank you. Bye.
-你準備好了嗎  -我準備好了
- You ready? - I am ready.
你知道我在想什么嗎
You know what I'm thinking?
冰淇淋
Ice cream.
這可能有些可笑  但有時
It's ridiculous, but sometimes
我真的覺得你知道我在想什么
I actually think you know what I'm thinking.
冰淇淋  冰淇淋  冰淇淋
Ice cream, ice cream, ice cream.
你知道嗎  我一個人待的時間太長了
Ugh. Do you know, I'm spending way too much time alone.
你想吃點冰淇淋嗎
You want to go get some ice cream?
你懂我
You read my mind.
我覺得可能就這樣了  蒂諾
I think this is it, Tino.
我覺得我們只能相依為命了
I think it's just gonna be you and me.
我不知道  這也挺好的  對嗎
I-I don't know. It's fine, right?
因為我愛你  你也愛我
Because I love you and you love me, and...
唯一重要的就是愛
Love is all that matters.
從哪兒得到的愛并不重要
It's not like it matters where you get your love.
只要有東西愛你  對嗎
As long as something loves you, right?
我能再來點嗎
Can I have some more?
你真貼心
Oh, you're so sweet.
你真可愛
You're so cute.
我愛你
Hi. I love you.
你為什么就不能是我男友呢
Why can't you be my boyfriend, huh?
你為什么就不能再給我點冰淇淋呢
Why can't you give me more ice cream?
還剩一針
--Okay, one more to go.
這些穿白大褂的人類
What's with these white-coat people
干嗎總是用尖東西扎我
sticking me with sharp things?
你按時喂他嗎
Now, do you feed him at regular times?
挺有規律的
Pretty regular.
你都給他吃什么
What do you give him?
吃的
Food.
狗糧  怎么了
Dog food. What?
或許你應該讓他多鍛煉些
Maybe give him more exercise.
多遛遛
Go on more walks.
沒問題
Sure.
扎針  我討厭扎針
Shots. I hate those shots.
好了  蒂諾
Okay, Tino.
我們來做運動吧
Let's do this, huh?
這是醫囑  過來吧
Doctor's orders. Come here.
好了  撿球去
All right, get the ball.
走了那么久  現在我又得撿球去
A long walk, and now I have to chase a ball?
把球撿回來  快點
Get the ball. Come on.
我為什么被這般懲罰
Why was I being punished like this?
蒂諾  快點  你是只狗
Tino, come on. You're a dog.
追球去  快去追
Get... chase the ball. Chase it.
-快點  蒂諾  -幸運兒
- Come on, Tino. - Lucky.
蒂諾  這真是太丟人了  好嗎
Tino, this is embarrassing, okay?
-快去吧  -對不起  今天不行
- Just, come on. - Sorry, not today.
-撿球去  -我沒那心情
- Get the ball. - I'm not in the mood.
之后我看見了她
And then I saw her.
一切都變了
And everything changed.
我的心激動起來
My heart was aflutter.
抓得真棒
What a catch.
蒂諾  把它帶回給我
Tino, bring it back to me.
你也與我感同身受嗎
Are you feeling what I'm feeling?
對不起
Hey, I'm sorry.
我的狗今天怪怪的
My dog's acting so weird today.
-不  沒事的  -我們走吧
- No, it's okay. - Come on, boy. Let's go.
快點  你想追這個嗎
Come on, are you gonna chase this?
-等一下  -你好
- Wait a minute. - Oh. Hey.
你和我都上肯特教授的課
You and I both have, uh, Professor Kenter.
是啊
Right. Yeah.
我叫艾爾
I'm-I'm Al.
好的  我叫瑪雅
Oh. Okay, I'm Maya.
-很高興認識你  -我很抱歉
- Nice to meet you. - I'm sorry...
瑪雅在說著話  但我不在聽
Maya was talking, but I didn't listen.
我腦子里都是她
All I could think of was her.
沒事的  我理解的
It's cool. I... No, I, understand.
它一遇到你的狗就像瘋了似的
So he's, like, acting crazy around your dog.
干嗎不肯呢
Why fight it?
我們聞起來好配
We smell great together.
我們開始天天都能見到羅西
We started seeing Roxy all the time.
不知為什么  艾爾也總是會來
For some reason, Al always came, too.
沒過多久
It wasn't long before...
我們就睡在一起了
We slept together.
我真的開始懂了
I'm really starting to get it now.
如果活著有意義  羅西就是那個意義
If there's a point, Roxy is the point.
慢著  出什么事了
Wait. What's going on?
瑪雅
Um, Maya?
我心里有些話
There's been something on my mind
一直想告訴你
that I've been wanting to talk to you about.
我記得那個汗濕的氣味
Oh, I recognize that sweaty smell.
我們已經在一起一段時間了
We've been together for a while now.
瑪雅  我想讓你成為我的妻子
--Maya, I want you to be my wife.
-艾爾  我的天哪  -事情不太對勁
- Al! Oh, my god! - Something's wrong here.
-我愿意  -瑪雅有危險
- Yes! - Maya's in trouble.
我愿意  過來
Yes! Yay! Come here!
-親愛的  我愿意  -太棒了
- Oh, honey, yes! - Yeah.
這兒有危險  躲到我身后  羅西
There is danger. Get behind me, Roxy.
我會保護大家的
I'll protect us all!
艾爾
Al!
我牽住蒂諾了
Okay. I got Tino. I got Tino. I got Tino.
等一下等一下
Okay, wait, wait. Hold on!
不  羅西  別這樣
No, Roxy. Stop it!
媽媽  拿一下這些花
Okay. Mom, hold the... Hold these.
好了  過來吧
Okay, come here. Come on.
-我覺得我們準備好了  -我們開始吧
- I think we're ready. - Okay, let's do this.
完美
Okay, perfect.
準備好
Ready.
你很嫉妒因為法倫有了孩子
You're jealous because Fallon's had her baby,
這使得你更偏執多疑了
and that's made you even more paranoid.
亞歷克西斯會被揍的
Alexis gonna get her butt whupped
-要是她還這么口無遮攔  -是吧
- she keep running off the mouth like that. - Right?
因為克里斯塔爾再也受不了這事了
'Cause Krystle's not gonna take much more of this.
-我沒有  -這太瘋狂了
- I haven't. - This is crazy.
我給你說了吧  我給你說了吧
I told you. I told you.
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh.
-什么  -打她  克里斯塔爾
- What? - Oh, get her, Krystle.
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh.
她的肚子里是什么聲音
What's all that noise in her stomach?
是她吃的東西的聲音嗎
Was it something she ate?
她們要殺了對方啊
Yo, they're trying to kill each other.
什么
What?
不
Oh, no.
-這是一個寶寶  -她在呼吸嗎
- It was a baby. - Is she breathing?
你要放松點  親愛的
You gotta relax, honey.
她在呼吸呢  好吧
She's breathing, okay?
也許我們應該叫醒她來確認一下
Uh, maybe we should wake her up just to be sure.
我不明白為什么他們要生個寶寶
I didn't understand why they got a baby.
這把他們的注意力都轉移走了
It took all their attention.
幸好羅西和我有所需的一切
Good thing roxy and I already had everything we needed.
我們彼此
Each other.
小寶寶
Hey, baby.
后來他們生了更多的寶寶
Then they went and got more babies.
看上去像是我的錯
Seemed like a mistake to me.
不久  我必須過著逃跑的生活了
Soon, I had to live my life on the run.
找到他了
Found him!
無處可逃
There was no escape.
我允許他們對我為所欲為
I let them do what they wanted to me.
我愿意做任何事情以便羅西可以安全
I'd do anything so that roxy could be safe.
那是我的使命  隨時保護她
That was my mission: To protect her at all times.
我想  說實話
I guess, if I was really honest,
我喜歡得到所有的關注
I liked all the attention.
隨著羅西和我漸漸變老
As roxy and I got older,
我們的關系更加穩固了
our connection grew stronger.
她也一直如我們初見時
And she never lost the spark
耀眼迷人
that drew me to her in the first place.
有一天  羅西去看獸醫了
One day, roxy went to the vet.
她就再也沒有回來過
And she never came back.
看我  看我
Look at me! Look at me!
每個人對我都很好
Everyone was good to me.
但隨著歲月的流逝  我很想念羅西
But as the years went by, I missed Roxy.
沒有她一切都不一樣了
It just wasn't the same without her.
蒂諾
Hey, tino.
Hey, Tino.
你知道我在想什么嗎
You know what I'm thinking?
是的
Yes.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
披薩
Pizza.
不是嗎
No?
不是披薩嗎
No pizza?
我不餓
I'm not hungry.
好吧
Okay.
蒂諾...
Tino...
你在想什么呢
What are you thinking?
蒂諾  你在想什么呢
Tino, what are you thinking?
我在想我準備好了
I'm thinking I'm ready.
這真的是我最美好的生活之一
One of my best lives, really.
我回來了
I'm back.
又一次
Again.
但是為什么呢
But why?
-小狗想要只小狗嗎  -你好啊  小朋友
- Puppies! Want a puppy? - Hey there, little fella.
-賣小狗了  -想買一只嗎
- Puppies for sale! - Want to buy one?
有想買小狗的嗎
Who wants a puppy?
你好啊
Hi!
我們又開始新生活了
Here we go again.
看看我抱的是什么
Look what I got. Huh?
我看到了
Yeah, I am looking.
看他多可愛啊
Look how cute he is.
你太不理智了
You know, it's-it's crazy.
誰來照顧他
Who's gonna take care of him?
我會的
I will.
好了  我給他取名華夫餅
Come on. I named him waffles.
不準進屋
Not inside.
吃吧
Come on.
我一直告訴她你會越長越大
I kept telling her you were going to get bigger.
所以她現在不太喜歡你了  對吧
Not so into you now, is she?
我哪里都沒有去過
I never went anywhere.
我從未玩耍過
I never played.
感覺就像沒有我日子也會一天天過去
It was like the days went on and on without me.
你有三十天的時間來處理掉這個
You have 30 days to deal with this.
當警察來的時候
When the officer came,
我以為又是要領我去參加找東西表演
I thought it was to take me to do find-and-show.
但她自己走了
But she left without me.
他很臟  我們要把他趕走
He's dirty. We're getting rid of him.
我們不能把狗趕走
We are not going to get rid of that dog.
夠了  我們要把他趕走
That's enough! We're getting rid of him.
我把他帶回來的  我們要照顧好他
I took him in here, and we're gonna take care of him.
你保證可以給他找個好家庭  是嗎
You'll make sure he finds a nice home, right?
一個負責任的人
Somebody responsible?
是的
Yeah.
快來  出來
Come on. Out.
動起來
Move it.
我們走  快來
Let's go. Come on.
動起來
Move.
再見  小狗
So long, doggie.
現在我應該走回家嗎
Now I'm supposed to walk home?
這似乎太不公平了
That didn't seem very fair.
但當我好好考慮后
But when I thought about it,
我不想回到那個家了
I didn't want to go back to that home.
快來  來這里
Come on. Over here.
看  媽媽
Look, mom.
看起來很有趣
That looks like fun.
坐  坐  你喜歡那個嗎
Sit. Sit. You like that?
已經很久沒有開心玩耍了
It's been so long since I've had fun.
她要去哪里
Where is she going?
我認識你嗎
Do I know you?
你身上有些東西
There's something about you.
是...你的味道
It's... your smell.
你有點臟臟的
You're a scruffy one.
你迷路了嗎
Are you lost?
你從哪里來的
Where are you from?
你有頸圈嗎
You got a collar?
我知道那個味道
I know that smell.
別害怕
Don't be afraid.
那是...在很久以前
It's... from a long time ago.
我之前來過這里嗎
Had I been here before?
真開心我能離開城市
I was so happy to leave the town behind.
我鼻子充滿了清新的味道
My nose was full of fresh new smells.
這里有個味道你永不會忘記
And then there are the smells you never forget.
火車  苔蘚
Train. Moss.
樹木  馬  垃圾
Trees. Horse. Garbage.
是小馬狗
It was horse-dog!
會是一樣的嗎
Could it be the same?
是一樣的耶
Ah, it was the same.
那是不是意味著伊森也曾在這
Could it mean Ethan was here, too?
那應該夠我們撐到月底
That ought to cover us to the end of the month.
伊森
Ethan?
不可能是他
That can't be him.
告訴弗雷德我會去鎮里
Tell Fred that I will be in town...
是他嗎
Is that him?
明日去結賬好嗎
...tomorrow to settle up, okay?
會跟他說的
Will do.
是他
It is him!
是他  太棒了
It's him! Yes!
太棒了  是他
Yes, it's him!
是我啊
It's me!
狗老大  貝利貝利貝利
Boss dog! Bailey, Bailey, Bailey
你的傻狗狗
doodle dog!
你從哪來的
Where'd you come from?
經過了這么世  我真的找到你了
After all these lives, I'd actually found him.
我找到了伊森
I found Ethan.
我敢打賭你餓了
I'm gonna make a bet you're hungry.
吃吧
Here you go.
看來是真餓壞了
You must be.
沒有人喜歡我煮的東西
Nobody likes my cooking.
不要這樣看著我
Don't look at me like that.
你不能留在這
You can't stay here.
你得回家去
You gotta go home.
你有主人
You belong to somebody.
家  對啊
Home. Yes.
對  我回家了
Yes, I'm home.
回家吧  狗狗
Go home, dog.
回家吧
Go home.
你是一條固執的狗狗  是嗎
You're a stubborn one, aren't you?
然后  周二晚間
Then, Tuesday night,
降雨量為76毫米
we got three tenths of an inch of rain.
確保它能找個好家
Be sure he gets a good home.
它是一條好狗
He's a good dog.
當然
Sure.
不不不  不要把我留在這
No. No, don't leave me here.
這里是收容站
This is a white-coat place.
我是你的
I belong with you.
再見  狗狗
So long, dog.
你想要離開這嗎
You want to get out of here?
你想走嗎
Do you want to go?
來吧  我們走
Come on, let's go.
我又坐回了前排
I was back in the front seat.
小家伙
Okay, buddy.
看來我們倆要相依為命了
Guess it's gonna be you and me.
還有那頭驢
And the donkey.
驢是什么
What's a donkey?
你上一次洗澡是什么時候
Now, when was the last time you got a bath?
真是條乖狗
That's a good boy.
洗好了
There you go. All right.
爬出去  我們走
Just step out. Out. Let's go!
干的好
There you go.
巴蒂
你會得到一個新的項圈
You're getting a new collar.
看起來它可沒有少吃
Doesn't look like he's missed too many meals.
-它體型很好  -嗯  是條好狗
- He's in good shape. - Yeah, he's a good boy.
是不是啊
Aren't you, huh?
但伊森似乎還是很傷心
But Ethan still seemed sad.
也許是因為他一個人睡
Maybe it was because he slept alone.
我想要幫他  可我不知道如何幫
I wanted to help him, but I didn't know how.
等等  等等
Wait. Wait.
等一下
Hold that thought.
貝利  就這么辦
Okay, Bailey, let's do this.
快點
Hurry.
快快快快快
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry.
就是這兒了
This is the place.
我在找...
I'm looking for...
快  卡莉  到這來  寶貝
Come on, Carly. Come here, girl.
-過來  卡莉  -過來吧  卡莉
- Come on, Carly. - Come on, Carly.
快來  卡莉
Come here, Carly.
能幫我開下門嗎
Can you get the gate for me?
-好的  媽媽  -謝謝
- Yes, mommy. - Thank you.
乖狗狗
Good girl.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
瑞秋
Rach.
快看  威爾
Oh, hey. Look, Will.
-外婆來了  -外婆
- Grandma's here. - Hi, grandma.
那又有那種氣味了
There's that smell again.
-最近感覺怎么樣  -挺好的
- How are you feeling? - I'm pretty good.
真是個驚喜
This is a surprise.
現在更濃了
It's stronger now.
我覺得我該給你們準備些吃的了
I thought I'd bring you some groceries.
-是漢娜  -謝謝
- It's Hannah! - Aw. Hmm, thanks.
你還在這
You're still here?
雖然你看起來不一樣了
Oh, you look different.
但聞起來還像餅干一樣
But you still smell like biscuits.
這是誰的狗
Who is this?
公園里的流浪狗
It's the, uh, stray from the park.
流浪狗  真的嗎
A stray? Really?
你好哇
Well, hello there.
多好一條狗啊
What a good dog.
它肯定不是流浪狗
Well, he's certainly not a stray,
因為它有項圈
'cause he's got a collar.
讓我看看
Let's see.
它的名字是巴蒂
His name is Buddy.
看看  它的主人是
Let's see. He belongs to...
伊森·蒙哥馬利
出來啊  伊森
Come on, Ethan.
我能聞出來你在里面
I can smell you in there.
我不想把你留在這
I don't want to leave you here.
但我想他應該不在家
But I guess he's not home.
嗨  伊森
Hi, Ethan.
嗨  漢娜
Hi, Hannah.
我把你的狗帶回來了
I brought your dog home.
你一定過的很辛苦吧
Must have been tough on you,
多年前就失去了丈夫
losing your husband after all those years.
嗯  所以我格外想念我的女兒
Yeah, it made me miss my daughter a lot.
然后  隨著孫子的出生
And then, with the new baby coming,
我覺得瑞秋和米格爾真的很需要幫手
I thought Rachel and Miguel could really use the help.
嗯
Yeah.
你要在這待多久啊
How long you get to stay for?
我不是來探親的  伊森
Uh, well, I'm... I'm not visiting, Ethan.
大概一個月前我就搬回來住了
I moved back about a month ago.
你搬了嗎
Y-you did?
歡迎回家
Welcome home.
謝謝
Thanks.
這個地方還跟以前一樣
Well, this place is still the same.
對啊
Yeah.
加油啊
Oh, come on.
那你呢
So, what about you?
你  你就再沒遇上某個人或
You... you never met anyone or...
找不到對的人
Never found the right fit.
我真的很固執
I'm really stubborn.
這點我知道
I know that.
當你把心思投入到一件事中  就是那樣
When you put your mind to something, that was that.
是的
Yeah.
這樣有助于把事情搞定
That's good for getting things done.
但是不利于發展感情
It's not so good for relationships.
好吧
Okay, well...
好吧  就這樣
Okay, here we go.
它們會互相舔臉
They're gonna lick faces.
這樣非常好
Well, look, this was really nice.
我得走了
I gotta go.
謝謝你  伊森
Thank you, Ethan.
等一下  什么
Wait, what?
拜托
Oh, come on!
謝謝你把我的狗帶回來
Hey, thanks for bringing back my dog.
不客氣  再見
You're welcome. Bye.
漢娜
Hey, Hannah.
我...
I, uh...
我欠你一句道歉
I owe you an apology.
為我們之間發生的事情道歉
For what happened to us.
以前的事
Back then.
別擔心
Well, don't worry.
那是很久很久以前了
It was a long, long time ago.
不
No.
我把你推開了
I pushed you away.
而且我那時對這個世界真的很憤怒
And I was... I was really mad at the world.
我只是想讓你知道
And I just want you to know that not a day goes by
我每一天都在為那樣做后悔
that I don't kick myself for doing that.
這就是那種流汗的味道
There's that sweaty smell.
你覺得
You think, uh,
如果我們一起做點什么
it'd be crazy if...
是件瘋狂的事嗎
we did something together?
你是想跟我約會嗎
Are you asking me out on a date?
我只是覺得如果我就看著你開車走了
Well, I just think that I'd be an all-time fool
那我就是個大大的白癡
if I just watched you drive away.
別說話了  快用鼻子吧
Enough talking. Use your nose.
不要
Then don't.
好的  現在你們做對了
Okay, now you're getting it.
好的  太棒了
Yes! Yes!
離這兒遠點
Get out of here.
給他們點空間
Give 'em some space.
那邊有一點  這就是為什么...
Few right there, that's why...
你好啊  小可愛
Hi, you little cutie pie.
我的水里有薄荷
Ew. My water has mint in it.
你開心嗎
You have a good time?
它們一旦開始互相舔臉
Once they started licking faces,
就沒人能阻止了
no one could stop them.
伊森終于得到他需要的了
Ethan finally had what he needed.
他很開心
He was happy.
我也很開心
I was happy, too.
不好意思  大家
Excuse me, everybody.
我想感謝你們今天能夠來到這里
I-I would like to thank you all for coming here today.
-這對漢娜和我很重要  -干杯
- It means a lot to Hannah and I. - Cheers.
我一直想要有個大家庭
I've always wanted a big family.
在一天之內  我就擁有了一個
All in one day, I've got one.
你沒說它有多大
You didn't tell me how big it was.
我只想說說我有多感恩
I just would like to say how grateful I am
我美麗的女孩
that my beautiful girl
重新回到了我的生命中
walked back into my life.
謝謝你
Thank you.
生命就是個謎
Life's a mystery.
干杯
Cheers.
我還想要做一件事
There was one thing I still wanted.
我想要他知道那是我
I wanted him to know it was me.
我們昨晚非常開心
We had so much fun last night.
我就是貝利
That I was Bailey.
昨晚真的很棒
What a great night.
別說了
Stop.
你很棒
You were amazing.
是的  你也很棒
Yeah. You, too.
-等等  貝利以前不就是這樣嗎  -是啊
- Wait, didn't Bailey used to do that? - Yeah.
狗狗都會這樣做
It's a dog thing.
貝利  我是貝利
Bailey. I'm Bailey.
肯定有辦法的
There's gotta be a way.
等等
Hmm. Wait.
這味道有點熟悉
That's familiar.
我聞到了...我的味道
I smelled... me.
你叼著什么呢
What do you got there?
你在哪發現的
Where did you find that?
你想玩嗎
You want to play?
準備好
Get ready.
你得追著這個
You have to really go after this one.
去追吧
Go get it.
好樣的
Good boy!
來  把它帶回來
Come on, bring it here.
不錯
Good one.
好
All right.
你自己去玩  好嗎
You go play, all right?
我得回去了
Gotta get back.
怎么了  你想要什么
What? What do you want?
這太瘋狂了
This is nuts.
好吧  哥們兒
All right, buddy.
你想來點好玩的
You want to go for the showstopper?
你想試試嗎  你想要吧
You want to try it? You want to get it?
準備好了嗎
Ready?
我準備好了
I am ready.
好了  去吧
Okay. Go!
你在哪里學的這招  哥們兒
Where did you learn how to do that, buddy?
你有點嚇到我的  狗老大
You are really starting to freak me out, boss dog.
沒錯  伊森  這就對了
Yes, Ethan, that's right.
我是你的狗老大  我是貝利
I'm your boss dog. I'm Bailey.
說出來
Say it.
狗老大
Boss dog?
你是狗老大
Are you the boss dog?
不會吧
No.
是的  是我  伊森
Yes. It's me, Ethan.
是我
It's me.
貝利
Bailey?
Bailey.
狗老大
Boss dog.
貝利  貝利  貝利  貝利   貝利
Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
太好了
Mmm, yeah.
所以  在我的狗生里
So, in all my lives as a dog,
這是我學到的東西
here's what I've learned.
很顯然  要玩得開心
Have fun, obviously.
無論何時
Whenever possible,
找到一些需要拯救的人  并拯救他們
find someone to save, and save them.
去舔那些你所愛的人
Lick the ones you love.
不為已經發生的事而悲傷
Don't get all sad-faced about what happened
也不為沒發生的事而苦惱
and scrunchy-faced about what could.
-活在當下就好  -去吧
- Just be here now. - Go!
好  去追吧
Okay, go get it.
-活在當下  -就這樣
- Be here now. - That's it.
這就是一條狗的使命
That's a dog's purpose.